## BURAK ERTAS, M.Eng

20 shore breeze dr, Toronto, Canada 514-834-6600 / burakertash@yahoo.com https://ca.linkedin.com/in/burak-ertas-644b3038/en

## **SUMMARY**

After having 4 years industrial experience on international projects, I arrived in Canada to enrich my skills with a master degree in civil engineering project management. Following completion of my master degree, I had a chance to work in one of the largest cable stay bridge projects in North America, New Champlain Bridge Project. I worked as a field engineer at the cable stay division of the project. I have completed my role successfully and the bridge was opened officially by 1st of July. I recently moved to Toronto and I am actively looking for job opportunities in GTA. I have experience in project and contract management along with field practice.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Engineering, Civil Engineering, Concordia University, Jan 2018 Bachelor's degree in civil engineering, Istanbul Technical University (ITU), 2006 to 2011

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# SSLC-Champlain Bridge Project, Cable Stay Bridge (\$4.2 Billion) - Field Engineer Montreal, May 2018 to May 2019

- -Worked as a night-shift engineer taking over ongoing activities (site works, design follow ups) from the day and ensuring night-shift team follows the same schedule.
- -Performed technical decisions during the night shift and deliver the product as per quality and design specs.
- -Performed daily progress report to management.
- -Performed PT (post-tensioning) bar stressing procedure and prior inspection.
- -Ensured all activities are met with Work Methods and HSE standards.
- -Performed design RFIs and ensure FW (field work) drawings met with the design.

## SIS IRELAND – Russia and Azerbaijan projects, July 2013 to July.2015

Project Manager (Stadiums for European Olympic Games and World Cup 2018)

- Building stadium pitch field including complicated civil and mechanical infrastructure
- Built pitches for big organizations such as European Cup, World Cup or Olympic Games
- Ensured for all contractual issues from bidding stage until handover the project.
- -Performed cost reports and cash flow analysis.
- Executed planning and cost control reports to management.
- Performed RFIs, RFQs and RFPs.

# YAPI MERKEZİ – Double track railway 140km/h - Cost Control Lead Engineer

Algeria, May 2012 to July 2013

- Worked as cost control lead engineer in a 23km double track railway project which links Zeralda suburbs to the capital city of Algeria.
- Developed and updated project cost forecasts periodically.
- Executed cash flow reports and informed project manager and head office.
- Performed indirect cost reports to individual departments to prevent overspending.
- Reported man hour budgets and coordinated with planning department.
- Prepared and submitted financial analysis reports.

## CADDELL - ENKA - US Embassy Compound - Project Engineer

Guinea Equatorial, May 2011 to May 2012

Planning and Cost Control Engineer (US New Embassy Compound)

- USA NEC project, New Embassy Compound in Guinea de Equatorial);
- Developed and maintained detailed product schedules.
- Executes daily progress reports.
- Developed and monitored project cost forecasts.
- Ensured adherence to recommended best practices such as the critical path method based on PERT.

## ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND SKILLS

## **University Course Projects**

- North Angola Railway Project/ Building Economics

We had a chance to get the real data from an actual bidding for the railway project in Angola. We (a group of 4 master students) analyzed the project by using building economics analysis and made a presentation if the project is rewarding from a building economic aspect. Detailed cost and revenue breakdowns is examined including long term loan payments.

# Certificate of Proficiency in French, Concordia University Continuing Education

- French language certificate B2 level

# **Software Knowledge**

-Autocad, Autocad Civil 3d, excel, word, outlook, Primavera P6, MS Project.

# **Corso restaurant & Sport Station Bar**

- Worked part time as restaurant & bar attender during my studies at Concordia.

# Actions Enfance-non profit organisation, Montreal

- Volunteer job for supporting disadvantaged children education in Montreal. Helped with storage inventory and promotion of sales.